https://spectrumhealthcare.com/privacy-statement/

Skip to content
Skip to nav
Important information on COVID-19
Privacy StatementAt Spectrum your privacy is important to us. Spectrum is proud of its long-standing commitment to maintaining the confidentiality and security of patients’ and clients’ personal information and has implemented practices to better protect the privacy of your personal information. As an essential part of our Quality Program, Spectrum collects, maintains, discloses, secures and destroys private patient and client information in accordance with the Ontario Personal Health Information Protection Act, 2004 (PHIPA) Personal Health Information Protection Act, which mandates the protection of your personal health information.As part of our commitment, we believe that our patients and clients should know what personal health information we collect, how we protect it and how to contact us.What is personal health information?Personal health information includes information about your health status, health history, health care number, eligibility for health care services, care needs and care plans that include identifying information about you such as your name, address, phone number and possibly some demographic information.Your Privacy RightsYou have the right to know how we collect, use and disclose personal information and to expect that, to the best of our ability, your personal information remains accurate, confidential and secure. Spectrum collects, uses, discloses and stores facts about you and your health to help provide health care or payments for health care. The information collected about you can only be used by authorized staff involved in providing you with your health care services. All Spectrum staff sign an individual confidentiality and privacy commitment upon employment and ensure that the collection of personal information is used for the specific use intended, and that consent is obtained for the collection, use or disclosure of personal information.You have the right to access the personal health information contained in your record, and to have this information corrected or amended. You also have the right to change or remove your consent. To do so, please contact the Privacy Officer at Spectrum Health Care.Our Privacy PrinciplesSpectrum uses the practices outlined in the Personal Health Information Protection Act, 2004 (PHIPA) and other applicable provincial to guide us in safeguarding personal health information. These principles are listed below.Accountability: Spectrum Health Care has assigned an individual to serve as Privacy Officer and has privacy policies and procedures in place.Identifying Purposes: Spectrum Health Care ensures that individuals know the purpose for which personal information is required prior to collection, use, or disclosure of the information.Consent: Consent is sought and obtained for the collection, use, or disclosure of any personal health information as required under legislation.Limiting Collection: The collection of personal health information shall be limited to that which is necessary for the purposes identified by Spectrum Health Care.Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention: Personal health information will not be used or disclosed for other than those purposes for which it was collected without the consent of the individual or as required by law. Personal health information shall be retained only as long as necessary for the purpose.Accuracy: Spectrum Health Care will ensure that personal health information is as accurate, complete and up-to-date as is necessary for the purposes for which it is to be used. Individuals have the right to request to have inaccurate information corrected.Safeguards: Appropriate security controls, for both technology and staff, are in place and maintained to ensure there is no unauthorized use or disclosure of personal information.Openness: Spectrum Health Care will readily make available to individuals the policies and procedures that support our commitment to privacy.Individual Access: Spectrum Health Care has a process for individuals, upon request, to access their personal health information and to challenge its accuracy.Challenging Compliance: An individual may challenge compliance to these principles through Spectrum Health Care’s Privacy Officer.If You Have Concerns…..Contact UsSpectrum Health Care has appointed a Privacy Officer to oversee, monitor and report all client and patient privacy issues and concerns. If you have any questions regarding this privacy statement, our business practices, or your dealings with us, please contact the Privacy Officer:Mail: Spectrum Health CareAttention: Privacy Officer, 2 Bloor St. East, Suite 2101 Toronto Ontario,
M4W 1A8Email: privacy.officer@spectrumhealthcare.comPhone: 416-964-4051Fax: 416-964-3952
How can we help you?Please fill in the information below and someone will contact you within the next business day.First & Last NameEmail *Phone NumberRelationship to SpectrumSelectI am a clientI am the relative/caregiver of a clientI am a prospective clientI am a health care professionalI am interested in learning more about SpectrumRecipient *General InboxHealth Care: TorontoHealth Care: PeelHealth Care: YorkSeniors for Seniors: TorontoSeniors for Seniors: Burlington, Hamilton & NiagaraSeniors for Seniors: Kitchener/Waterloo & areaSeniors for Seniors: Guelph, Georgetown & Dufferin CountySeniors for Seniors: OttawaSeniors for Seniors: KingstonSeniors for Seniors: Collingwood/MuskokaSeniors for Seniors: LondonFoot CareSubjectService RequestGeneral InquiryComplimentFeedbackComplaint/ConcernBusiness Opportunity/PartnershipMessageSubmit Message
Thank you for your message!
We will contact you within the next business day.
Close
